has a lot of implications to actual future application in architecture, and in this case, here you see a house, that's for a developer in China, and it's actually a four-story glass box. It's still with that glass box because we still want that visual access, but now it's sheathed with this thermo-bimetal layer, it's a screen that goes around it, and that layer can actually open and close as that sun moves around on that surface. In addition to that, it can also screen areas for privacy, so that it can differentiate from some of the public areas in the space during different times of day. And what it basically implies is that, in houses now, we don't need drapes or shutters or blinds anymore because we can sheath the building with these things, as well as control the amount of air conditioning you need inside that building. I'm also looking at trying to develop some building components for the market, and so here you see a pretty typical double-glazed window panel, and in that panel, between those two pieces of glass, that double-glazing, I'm trying to work on making a thermo-bimetal pattern system so that when the sun hits that outside layer and heats that interior cavity, that thermo-bimetal will begin to curl, and what actually will happen then is it'll start to block out the sun in certain areas of the building, and totally, if necessary. And so you can imagine, even in this application, that in a high-rise building where the panel systems go from floor to floor up to 30, 40 floors, the entire surface could be differentiated at different times of day depending on how that sun moves across and hits that surface. And these are some later studies that I'm working on right now that are on the boards, where you can see, in the bottom right-hand corner, with the red, it's actually smaller pieces of thermometal, and it's actually going to, we're trying to make it move like cilia or eyelashes. This last project is also of components. The influence -- and if you have noticed, one of my spheres of influence is biology -- is from a grasshopper. And grasshoppers have a different kind of breathing system. They breathe through holes in their sides called spiracles, and they bring the air through and it moves through their system to cool them down, and so in this project, I'm trying to look at how we can consider that in architecture too, how we can bring air through holes in the sides of a building. And so you see here some early studies of blocks, where those holes are actually coming through, and this is before the thermo-bimetal is applied, and this is after the bimetal is applied. Sorry, it's a little hard to see, but on the surfaces, you can see these red arrows. On the left, it's when it's cold and the thermo-bimetal is flat so it will constrict air from passing through the blocks, and on the right, the thermo-bimetal curls and allows that air to pass through, so those are two different components that I'm working on, and again, it's a completely different thing, because you can imagine that air could potentially be coming through the walls instead of opening windows. So I want to leave you with one last impression about the project, or this kind of work and using smart materials. When you're tired of opening and closing those blinds day after day, when you're on vacation and there's no one there on the weekends to be turning off and on the controls, or when there's a power outage, and you have no electricity to rely on, these thermo-bimetals will still be working tirelessly, efficiently and endlessly. Thank you. (Applause) (Applause)
tiene muchas posibilidades para futuras aplicaciones en la arquitectura. Aquí se ve una casa para un desarrollador en China, que es una caja de vidrio de cuatro pisos. Todavía es una de caja vidrio porque queremos acceso visual, pero ahora está forrada con esta capa termobimetal, es una pantalla que la rodea, y esa capa puede en realidad abrirse y cerrarse según el movimiento del sol en la superficie. Además de eso, también puede detectar áreas privadas para que puedan diferenciarse de las zonas públicas del mismo espacio a distintas horas del día. Esto quiere decir básicamente que, en las casas de ahora, ya no necesitemos cortinas, persianas ni celosías porque es posible cubrir el edificio con estas cosas, así como controlar la cantidad de aire acondicionado necesario en el edificio. También estoy tratando de desarrollar algunos componentes de construcción para el mercado. Aquí ven un típico panel de ventanas de vidrio doble, y en ese panel, entre las dos piezas de vidrio, el doble acristalamiento, estoy tratando de hacer un sistema termobimetal para que cuando el sol golpee la capa exterior y caliente la cavidad interior, el termobimetal comience a curvarse, y lo que realmente va a pasar es que empezará a bloquear el sol en ciertas áreas del edificio, o en todas, si es necesario. Imaginen que eso se aplicara incluso en un edificio alto donde los sistemas de paneles van de una planta a otra hasta 30 o 40 pisos, toda la superficie podría variar en diferentes momentos del día dependiendo del reflejo del sol en la superficie. Estos son algunos proyectos futuros en los que estoy trabajando que están en los recuadros, donde se puede ver, en la parte inferior derecha, en rojo, que son en verdad pequeñas piezas de metal térmico, que tratamos de hacer mover como cilios o pestañas. Este último proyecto también es de componentes. La inspiración —y si han notado, una de mis áreas de influencia es la biología— proviene del saltamontes. Los saltamontes tienen un sistema respiratorio diferente. Respiran a través de unos orificios en los costados llamados espiráculos, y llevan el aire que pasa a través de su cuerpo para enfriarlos. En este proyecto, trato de ver cómo podemos considerar eso también en la arquitectura, cómo llevar aire a través de los agujeros en las paredes de un edificio. Aquí pueden ver algunos de los primeros estudios de bloques por donde efectivamente pasan los agujeros. Esto es antes de instalar el bimetal térmico, y esto es después de instalarlo. Disculpen, es un poco difícil de ver, pero en la superficie, se pueden observar las flechas rojas. A la izquierda, se ve cuando hace frío y el bimetal térmico es plano para que impida al aire pasar a través del bloque, y a la derecha, el bimetal térmico se curva y permite que el aire pase. Estos son dos componentes distintos en los que estoy trabajando, y de nuevo, es algo completamente diferente porque pueden imaginar que el aire pudiera potencialmente pasar a través de las paredes en lugar de abrir las ventanas. Quiero dejarlos con una última impresión sobre el proyecto, o este tipo de trabajo y el uso de materiales inteligentes. Cuando están cansados de abrir y cerrar las persianas todos los días, cuando están de vacaciones y no hay nadie los fines de semana que encienda y apague los aparatos, o cuando hay un apagón y se quedan sin electricidad, estos bimetales térmicos seguirán trabajando sin descanso, de manera eficiente y para siempre. Gracias. (Aplausos) (Aplausos)